VAL YERMAN

40 Equestrian Dr, Burlington, NJ 08016

Cell: 919-649-8084 yermanv@gmail.com

More than 20 years of project supervision experience in a variety of commercial and residential business settings.

Accustomed to meeting aggressive time limes and working with sensitive documents.

Proven ability to effectively manage and supervise multiple trades to complete field work in a professional and safe controlled manner.

Committed to Safety.

Ability to problemsolves and planning daily schedules.

Successful organization and overall supervision of construction projects to completion.

Superb communication skills & the ability to interface effectively with all professional and construction personal.

Selected to manage and train new in house laborers on routine construction methods and company standard operating procedures.

Experienced in Microsoft Office 2010, PRIMAVERA, PROLOG, Scheduling, Change Order Log, and Updates. CAD

Experienced with (scope)

EXPERIENCE

NOV/2018 – MAY/2019 SUPERINTENDENT/PROJECT MANAGER, LEGACY SERVICE USA, SOUTHAMPTON, PA

Compile and plan a budget, cost estimates, and other financial estimates

Coordinate, plan, and manage schedules for contractors and subcontractors

Develop construction project with General Contractors

Order and manage materials and equipment

Provide internal reporting and projections for inventory

Oversee and supervise construction project progress and provide reports on timeline, progress, and adjustments

Ensure all legal requirements, building and safety codes, safety inspections, city guidelines, and local and state regulations are met

Perform the tasks of a cost estimator

Ensure that projects are completed on time and within budget

Train field staff in safety, work skills, and efficiency;

Resolve complains and grievances; assist with discipline when necessary;

2016 - NOV/2018

SUPERINTENDENT, CVMNEXT CONSTRUCTIONS, KING OF PRUSSIA, PA.

Supervised all construction and activities of large 6 million new constructions UPS Uniondale, NY,

Philadelphia Horticultural Center renovation and several smaller projects.

2010 - 2016

OWNER, ANGELS HOME CONSTRUCTIONS, BURLINGTON, NJ.

Owner and operator of the General Construction company with up to 22 employees and about 950 K annual budgets.

2008 - 2010

SUPERINTENDENT, SAMBE GENERAL CONTRACTOR COMPANY, PENNSAUKEN, NJ

Supervised a 23 million dollar new construction of Art & Interactive Multimedia Building for College of New Jersey.

Oversee and coordinate all activities on site

Supervising all self-performed activities

Working with architects and owners

Performing other superintendent's and project engineer's duties such as job site safety, site inspections, meetings with architects and owners, daily reports, Primavera 5 reports, scheduling, Change Orders, RFI, etc.

2007 - 2008

SUPERINTENDENT, ARCHER WESTERN CONTRACTORS INC., GENERAL CONTRACTOR COMPANY, RALEIGH, NC.

Supervised a 96 million dollar new construction of Dempsey E. Benton Water Treatment Plant.

Supervised all electrical, mechanical, instrumentation, and other activities on site.

Supervised self-performed activities such as excavation, concrete, yard, and mechanical piping installations and processed equipment installation.

Reported directly to Senior Project Superintendent.

Created RFI's, Change Orders and PO's;

Reviewed submittals and did other engineering and PM duties.

Completed over 15 different Safety classes and

Manager training programs and awarded Diploma from AWC for Extra Ordinary Safety Efforts and Accomplishment.

2006-2007

SUPERINTENDENT/FOREMAN, POWER DESIGN INC, RALEIGH, NC.

Supervised the installation of power distribution systems and all types of electrical, fire alarm, security, control, and telephone services for large High Rise project. Supervised up to 40 men crew.

Organized labor and material delivery/use formulti-million dollar commercial projects.

Managed Subcontractors.

2006-2006

PROJECT MANAGER, CONSTRUCT CORPS, RALEIGH, NC

Project manager for JW Grand General Contractor Company. NCSU 15 million dollar renovation project.

2004-2006

ELECTRICAL JOURNEYMAN, PORT CITY ELECTRIC COMPANY, RALEIGH, NC.

Worked on all types of new construction and renovations of services and branches. Provided underground rough, slab rough, wall rough, overhead rough and any types of electrical, fire alarm, security, control.

The position included material management and coordination with General Constructor.

2000-2004

ELECTRICAL JOURNEYMAN, CODE ELECTRIC COMPANY, RALEIGH, NC Worked on more than 20 various projects including hospitals, schools, offices and pharmaceutical facilities

1995-1999

CHIEF ENGINEER, GAP-53 (THE LARGEST STATE AUTOMOTIVE TRANSPORTATION COMPANY), BELARUS

Supervised constructions of new technical service and repair facilities

EDUCATION

1994-1995

M.S. IN INDUSTRIAL AND CIVIL CONSTRUCTION, MOSCOW STATE CONSTRUCTION UNIVERSITY.

Credentials Evaluation Report from Career Consulting International. May 23, 2006: Education is Equivalent to U.S. Master of Science in Civil Engineering.

1990-1994

B.S. IN INDUSTRIAL AND CIVIL CONSTRUCTION, MOSCOW STATE CONSTRUCTION UNIVERSITY.

1996-1997

THE CARL DUISBERG GESELLSCHAFT INTERNATIONAL ADVANCED MANAGEMENT SCHOOL (CDF), GERMANY.

SKILLS

OSHA 30 certificate 2017.

Heavy Equipment Operator: Operate excavators, loaders, hoes, dozers, crane, etc.